Hanchett, Walter Papers 6120
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Walter Hanchett Papers
1774-2000
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Hanchett, Walter
6120
25.5 cubic feet
25.1 linear ft.
Papers.
5806218
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 06, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 25, 2015
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Slavic Americans -- New York (State) -- Cortland; Russian Americans -- New York (State) -- Cortland; Ukrainian Americans -- New York (State) -- Cortland; Socialism -- New York (State) -- Cortland; Communism -- New York (State) -- Cortland; Hanchett, Walter
5806218
- Phonograph records. (Box 1)
  - Record Album, 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Russian, Ukrainian and English; 10 records and 2 catalogue books
- Lusk Committee; Subject files on immigration, research notes and supporting documentation.. (Box 2)
  - Streets, 1908-1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Tom's Blue Forms, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Spring 1975
  - Cortland Russian/Ukrainian Mutual Aid Society: Documents, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1917+1918 Military Draft Data (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cortland Rural Cemetery, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Belorussians (katzaps) in Cortland, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Search for Louis Litonovich I&N File, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    13 Nov 1984
  - Laws relating to Mizha immigration documents, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Title partially illegible, resembles "Mizha"
  - Immigration file on Mizher part I duplicate copies, 1948-1951 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Material mailed to me 21 June 1990 Set #2 working copy (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Materials mailed ot me June 15 + Sept 24 1990 set#2 working copies (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Immigration files mailed to me June 15 + Sept 24 1990--set #2 working copies (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Immigration File on Mizher Part II duplicate (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Immigration file on Mizher Part II, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Materials mailed to me June 15+Sept 24, 1990 set #1 file copy (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Immigration file on Mizher Part II, 1920-1953 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Mizher Ins FOIA materials, 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Materials mailed to me 21 June 1990 set #1 -- file copy (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Mizher Case: Arguments + Appeals pg. 197+, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Court transcripts
  - Mizher case through p. 194 (up to summing up), 1920-1923 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Mizher case legal precedent, 1920-1923 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Man in Rochester Arrested Jan 1920 + charged with selling communist manifesto (Weinberger papers) (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Church episode, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Trial summations (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Mizher talk, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Info on Novyi Mir + the search for it, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Manifesto+Program, Constitution, Rept. To the Communist International Xerox Pamphlet No. 1 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Mizher: Correspondence due. Re: Mizher, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - File 281, Box 6, Folder 14, 1919-1920 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Tusk Committee File 281, Box 6, file 16, 1913-1921 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Paper proposal on Mizher case, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Disposal of Cases, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - File 33, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Contains mailing package
  - Search for Mizher I+N file FOI matters, 1983-1989 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Search for Mizher 1969+, for Victoria Antonovich, for Walter Riyoka, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Mizher Displays, 1916-1919 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Mizher basic use in research, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - NY State 160+161, Fed. Of 16 Oct. 1918 of Cases, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - 1920 fed census list of primers in country/city jail 6 Jan. 1920 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Notes on Sources (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - How many, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Lusk Committee File 281, Box 6, Folder 15, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Rybka refito, File 281, Box 6, Folder 15 (Sept. - Nov. 22, 1919 First Xerox copy (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Albany Archives Notes File 281 Box 6 Folder # 16 duplicate Xerox, 1919-1920 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Arrest group--Basic data (Box 2, Folder 45)
    Notes on Census data
  - Immigration Notes, 1890-1914 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    Contains "Working papers: The Rockefeller Foundation Ethnic Studies" Richard Gambino, 1975
  - Permission Forms (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - State Archives, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    October 1988
  - Selected Rybka Letters Sept.-Nov. dup. copies, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    Sept.-Nov.1919
- Local History Sources and Genealogical Material. Red Scare, deportation subject files, including Government documents and other first degree sources. Copyright restrictions/releases.. (Box 3)
  - Picture History of Virgil, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Picture Booklet "As We Were: A Picture History of Virgil"
  - Translations and Examples of Tsarist passport and Customs Docs., 1879-1914 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Russian and English
  - Internal Passport System, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Pale, Anti-Semitism, Pogroms in Belorussia/Ukraine, 1881-1980 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Passports, 1977-1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    English and Russian
  - Internal Passport from Laura Jones and other docs + notes, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Info Re: Tsarist Military Obligation + Military Matters, 1874-1969 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    English and Russian; contains two small books on military dress and war
  - Oral History, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Contains the "Tape-Recorded Interview", a small book.
  - Restrictions on Quo from Letters and Archival Sources, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Rundell "Relations Between Historical; Researchers and Custodians of Source materials, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Re: Copyright, releases, and Similar Matters, 1984-1992 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Freedom of Info Act and Procedures, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Roots Searching, 1984-1990 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Ruthernians, 1979-1986 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Illegible but possibly relating to the Rusyn language
  - Carpatho-Rus, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Roots searching in Poland, Czech and Slovakia and Hungary, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Belorussia/Roots Search, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Brest Province (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Bessarabia/Moldavia (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Morphet paper on Curzon Line, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Polish/Russian border; Curzon Line, related matters documents and secondary accounts, 1919-1984 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - German Tours in Slovakia and Upper Hungary: A Genealogical Gazetteer, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - German Genealogy and Mennonite Family History, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Report of the Joint Legislative Committee (1939) (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Who's Who in Socialist America (Circa 1914) (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - ACLU Papers, 1912-1982 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Legal History- General, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Louis Post material from Wm. B Wilson Papers, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - US Senate Judic. Committee Charges of Illegal Practices, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    January 19th 1921
  - Post Deportations delirium, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    Also cited 1913-1921
  - Colyers Deportation Hearings, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    June 5, 1920
  - Panunzio. Deportation Cases of 1919-1920 Entire Book (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - US Congress House Committee on Immigration and National Communist and Anarchist Deportation Cases, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    April 21 to 24, 1920
  - Colyer, Immigration, Deportation and Organized labor (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Kelleher Memo of 26 May 20 to Burke/Hoover Xerox Copy of Print Out, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    26 May 1920
- Deportation subject files (continued), second degree sources, articles from The Liberator. Cortland County Chronicles.. (Box 4)
  - Cortland County Chronicles, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Wm. B Wilson re: deportations, 1919-1920 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Walsh-Sterling 'Reports' to Judiciary Committee of Senate; Walsh Reply to Sterling Report, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    February 5, 1923
  - Kelleher 17 may 20 report to Burke re: Amalgamated Clothing, Workers of America and Frankfurter. Xerox of Print Out, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    17 may 20
  - Deportation Correspondence and Other Related Documents Between Justice and Immigration/ Labor March 1919- Oct. 1920, 1919- 1920 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    March 1919 - Oct. 1920
  - US Cong House Committee on Rules. "Atty Gen. Palmer (Palmer Hearings) on Charges made Against the Dept of Justice by Louis F Post" Part I, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Collective Biographical Data re: "the 12" and persons other than defendants in the Colyer case, 1920-1921 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - David Williams, "The Bur. Of Investigation and its Critics, 1919-21: the Origins of Federal Political Surveillance", 1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Journal of American History, Dec. 1981
  - Palmer Hearings, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Points 2 and 3, see charges against in Point 3, ff 722-26
  - Report on Illegal Practices of the Department of Justice, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    National Popular Government League
  - Material re: Frederick Howe in Wm. B. Wilson Papers, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    May 29 and Oct. 9 1919
  - Administration of Immigration Laws Parts 1 and 2, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    US Congressional House Committee on immigration and Naturalization, March 30 and 31 and April 6 1920
  - A. le Sueur, Brief in Deportation Case in Minnesota (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - "Louis F. Post and the Red Scare of 1920" Prologue (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Spring 1920, Candeloro
  - Freedom of Speech (1920) (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Chafee, author
  - 'American Political Trials", 1981 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Belknap (ed)
  - "Political Trials" (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Christenson, Ron
  - "Deportation of Aliens from the U.S. to Europe" Excerpts (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Clark, author. Undated.
  - 'A. Mitchell Palmer' (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Cohen, author. Undated.
  - "At the Point of Production: The Local History of IWW", 1981 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Conlin, Joseph R (ed)
  - Conspiracy Trials in America 1919-1953: List of Microfilms (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Does not actually contain microfilms
  - "The Society of Deer Island" and Other D.I. materials, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    January-February 1920, "By One of Its Members"
  - Boston Evening Transcript 31 march - 30 April 1920 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    31 March - 30 April 1920
  - Christian Science Monitor 9 April - May 10 1920 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    9 April - 10 May 1920
  - Colyer Case Boston Herald Coverage, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Boston Globe 25 March - 11 May 1920 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    25 March - 11 May 1920
  - Investigation of NPBh and Colyer case People, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    Bureau of Investigation (Hoover), June 1920
  - "Lewis Corey (Louis C. Fraina), 1892-1953: A Bibliography with Autobiographical Notes", 1963 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    Corey, Esther. Labor History, Spring 1963
  - "Freedom Knows 20 Limits", 1920 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    Darrow, "Attorney for the Damned", Chicago Tribune, May-Aug 1920
  - Easterly MA/Ph.D. Theses, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    August 10, 1970
  - "Gov. Alfred E. Smith" Chapter 9: "Civil Liberties" (Box 4, Folder 31)
    Eldot, author
  - "American reign of terror" (Box 4, Folder 32)
    FeuerLicht, Roberta Strauss
  - Gitlow Case, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - "Social Basis of American Communism", 1961 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    Glazer
  - "Political Repression in Modern America" Chapters 5 and 6, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    R. Goldstein
  - "Christianity and Socialism in America, 1900-1920", 1952 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    Handy, Robert T
  - "The Labor Spy": Excerpts, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    Howard, Sydney
  - 'Palmer Raids" Xerox, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    Hoyt, Edwin
  - "Leon Trotsky in NY" (Box 4, Folder 39)
    Jensen, Ronald J
  - "Impossible Dream" pgs. 297-350 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    Poll, John.
  - "Some Problems in the Writing of Labor History", 1965 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    Kahn, Herman
  - "Palmer Raids", 1948 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    Labor Research Association Edited by Robert W. Dunn
  - "Labor Voice" (Box 4, Folder 43)
    Lombardi
  - "The Red Conspiracy", 1920 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    Mereto, Joseph J
  - "Peasant Pioneers" Excerpts (Box 4, Folder 45)
    Miller, K.
  - Articles on Lodgers, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    August 1973; Modell and Hareven
  - "Meaning of Freedom of Speech" Chapters 6 and 13 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    Murphy, Paul
  - "Civil Liberty in War Time", 1919 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    O'Brian, John Lord; January 17 and 18, 1919
  - "Progressives and Anarchism: Judge Henry D. Clayton and the Abrams Trial", 1985 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    Polenberg, R. Fall, 1985
  - CCHC Revisions Needed (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Stories to Pursue later: Grover Hart 'Papers", etc. Spencer Williams, 1920-1934 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    Dryden, NY. Ithaca, NY.
  - Liberator: General Info, 1920-1937 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Liberator March 1918 - March 1919 Xeroxes, 1918-1919 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    March 1918 - March 1919
  - Liberator Jan. 1920 - Dec. 1920 Xeroxes (Box 4, Folder 54)
    Jan. 1920 - Dec. 1920
  - Liberator 1921 Xeroxes (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Liberator 1922 Xeroxes (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Liberator Jan. - May 1923 Xeroxes (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Liberator Slides (Box 4, Folder 58)
    Jan. 20 - June 21; Contains Film Slides in original Kodak box
  - "Art and Politics: Cartoonists of the Masses and Liberator", 1973 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    Fitzgerald, Richard
- Red Scare research notes, map file.. (Box 5)
  - Presentations at FEEFHA, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Minneapolis, June 1996
  - FEEFHS talk on Documents, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Talk, docs, transparencies
  - University of Minnesota "Immigration History Research Center", 1984-1996 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Izyaslov Essay from Ist mist I sil (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Russian
  - Picture identifications and related Materials, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    NY State Archives
  - Germans in Volynia, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    July - Aug. 1991
  - Auburn, NY and Rochester, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    February 21 1987
  - Form for Requesting military records information, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - New Haven, 1964-1984 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    May 13, 1964; 27 Dec. 1984
  - SS Peter and Paul Church -- Syracuse, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    8 October 1984
  - "The Strike Files" (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Actual title illegible
  - Rajzl, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    January 29, 1995
  - History Club Talk Notes (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Syracuse Trips (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Owega Street School (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - New Slavic Immigrants in Cortland County and nearby, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Map Folder (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Russian; contains Soviet-era maps, diagrams
  - Library of Congress, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    April 17, 1989
  - NY Public Library, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Ukr. Sources NYC/Jersey City area, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    30 December 1985
  - Jensen, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    8 October 1984. "Leon Trotsky in NYC"
  - Guide to Sources in Michigan State University Libraries, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    American Labor History
  - American Society of Germans from Russia, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    June 30, 1995
  - Guide to the MSS Collection (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Tamiment Library
  - Natural Archives and related institutions, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    May 3, 1983, Washington, DC
  - Regional Federal Archives-Bayonne (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Bayonne, NJ
  - Immigration Bureau numbers and lists of deporting in Cortland cases, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    May 21, 1980
  - Immigration, naturalization, and Census records, 1978-1982 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - NY State Archives, 1982-1988 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    4 August 1988; 20 Feb. 1983; 5 Dec. 1982
  - File Numbers and FBI Index Cards (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Nat'l Archives; Williams notes on FBI records
  - PAWA SS with Comments and Corrections, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    April 13, 1989; Feb. 14, 1989
  - Cortland County Historical Society (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Central NY and Cortland newspapers, 1919-1920 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    Nov. 1919 - Aug. 1920 Notes
  - "The US Immigration Commission: A Study of Nativism in Government"; "Aliens and Espionage: Nativism in NY, 1917-1920", 1984 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    Session of Conference on NY State History at St. John Fisher College, June 1984, WH Chair
  - "A Bibliographic Guide", 1980 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    Official Publications of NY State, August 1980
  - NY State Department of labor Reports and Data, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    October 1919
  - AFL Archives, Washington (Box 5, Folder 37)
    Department of Labor, Washington
  - Courthouse and Public Library (Box 5, Folder 38)
    Notecards and notes
- MSS drafts, Fragmentors, chronology/miscellaneous notes and photocopies.. (Box 6)
  - City Directory Collections, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Dilemmas of Russian Nationalism, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Census of 1920, etc. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - A letter in Russian, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Notes and Clippings, 1993-1998 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - To do -- locally and beyond (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Key to Russian Typewriter Ball. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Contains photographs and negatives.
  - Questions (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Cortland Are: Historical (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Book Reviews and Readings, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Notes from Cortland Newspapers (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Rybka Reports Notes, 1919 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    Oct. - Nov. 1919
  - Cortland Standard Notes Professor Ralston, 1930-1979 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    By Professor Ralston
  - Chronologies of Events, 1919-1920 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Rybka Reports and Notes, 1919 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Cortland Standard and Homer Republican, 1919-1923 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    1919-1920; 1923
  - Chapters 1 and 2 Manuscripts and Drafts, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    9 Dec. 1991
  - Active manuscript (Box 6, Folder 19)
    "September"
  - Drafts: Summaries for (Box 6, Folder 20)
    Title partially Illegible; document titled 'Walt's project - Draft"
  - Wickwire and Cortland (Box 6, Folder 21)
    Years spanning 1911-1970's
  - Larry's Chronology (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Copies of articles, newsclippings, and notes on the Red Scare, military intelligence, Wickwire files, ACLU, Lusk Committee with MS notes. Book reviews.. (Box 7)
  - "Red Scare" before 1919 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Bureau of Investigation and Department of Justice Documents (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "The Boss", 1990 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Theohanis and Cox
  - Labor Spies and Agents: Provocateur (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Military Intelligence (Box 7, Folder 5)
    "The Great red Scare: Political repression in Modern America"
  - American Protective League (Box 7, Folder 6)
    And similar Anti-radical organizations. Chafee, "Freedom of Speech" (1920). Said to have participated in Lusk Committee raids in summer 1919. LRA, 1921
  - US department of labor (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Industrial Conditions (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Mention of 1974
  - Brass Valley (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Suller Case, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - NY State Laws Affecting Freedom of Expression and Political Views (Box 7, Folder 11)
    1916, 1917, 1920
  - Governor Al Smith and Lusk Laws and Criminal Anarchy Cases and Pardons (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Governor Al Smith, Lusk Laws, Criminal Anarchy Cases and Pardons (Box 7, Folder 13)
    Around 1920
  - ACLU and Labor Department Correspondence, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    re: those aliens to be pardoned by Governor Smith
  - Palmer and Lusk Raids: General (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Palmer and Lusk Raids, General (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Other Pardons and Amnesty; Political Prisoners (Box 7, Folder 17)
    Some documents 1920-1921
  - Workers' Defense Committee; American Workers Defense Union; national defense Committee, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    April 12, 1923
  - Abrams Case, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    One document references march 23, 1920
  - Expulsion of 5 NY State Assemblymen in 1920 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Expulsion of Victor L. Berger from US House of Representatives (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Bureau of Investigation Activities and Red Scare Outside of NY State (Box 7, Folder 22)
    Contains magazine Xerox from 1979
  - Lusk Committee's British Connection (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Copies of articles and notes from books on the Red Scare, Department of Labor, sedition and radicalism, citizens groups and lobbies, NYS legislature, immigration laws.. (Box 8)
  - Post Impeachment and Related Hearings, 1920-1921 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    April 1920- July 1921
  - Waning of Red Scare (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Anti-radicalism of Post Red Scare Period (Box 8, Folder 3)
    One mentions 1987
  - Organizational Structure (Box 8, Folder 4)
    NY State Department of Labor
  - Criminal Anarchy, Criminal Syndicalism, Red Flag Laws, Sedition Laws and Bills/Cases (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Legal Aspects of Lusk and Federal Raids, 1920 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Court Cases (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Re: Criminal Anarchy in NY State; One document 1971
  - Climate of Opinion (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Climate of Opinion (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Climate of Opinion (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Education (Box 8, Folder 11)
    1928;1940;1995
  - Associated Industries, Inc. and New York League for Americanism Pressure Groups and Lobbies, 1920 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    March 1920
  - Commissioner General of Immigration Annual reports, 1920-1980 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    History of Immigration Service
  - New Legislation on Immigration, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    1980's; Contains magazine
  - Committee on Exploitation of Immigrants Report, 1917-1919 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    NY State Legislative; Aril 1917 - March 1919
  - Immigration and Deportation Statutes (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Immigration and Deportation Rulings and Practices (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Immigration, Deportation Rulings and Practices (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Immigration, Deportation Rulings and Procedures, 1916-1919 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Immigration, Deportation Rulings and Procedures, 1911-1917 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    NY State Reports
  - Attempts to Prevent Naturalization of Alien Radicals and to Achieve De-naturalization (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Alternatives to Deportation, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    13 February 1987
- Photocopies of articles with notes on Cortland, popular culture, ethnic groups, religion, arrests of Reds, includes newspaper clipping and bibliographical file. Book. From Many Roots, Cortland County Chronicles, Volume 4, 1986.. (Box 9)
  - General Information Cortland and Pre-Arrest Info on Slavic Community (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Industries other than W
  - Industries other than W, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - US and NY General, Late to 1919 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - US and NY General Late 1919 to - (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Local Setting and Contemporary Ads Situation in Nearby Situation, 1920-1994 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - C.S. Editorials and Cartoons ca. 1919-1920 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Radicals in other Upstate Cities, 1919-1920 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Popular Culture, 1919-1920 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Italians in Cortland (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Population Data, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Census documents
  - Home proprietorship, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Summary of CD and CS Articles re: Cortland Radicals, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Nov. 23 1919 Arrests and related Actions to End of Dec. 1919 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    Nov. 23 - Dec. 1919
  - Arrests and related Stuff Jan. 1 1920 - (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Jan. 1 1920
  - Cortland Jail, 1917 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - First Congregation Church Photos, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 16)